覚！
Satoru!
Saki!
早季～！
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
Yeah, I’m fine.
うん 私は
We’re lucky we weren’t buried alive.
生き埋めになんなくて よかった
I don’t think we can get out, though.
でも 出られないんじゃない？
とりあえず
毒ガスは入ってこないかな…
Well, at least we’re safe from the poisonous gas.
We could start chipping away at the ceiling to get out.
ねえ 上 もうちょっと崩したら
外に出られるんじゃない？
Don’t think so.
いや 外の音が
全然 聞こえないから
I can’t hear anything outside, so
I’d say we’re buried in pretty deep.
たぶん
まだまだ 結構あるんじゃないかな
I see.
そっか…
ねえ
Hey.
Hmm?
真理亜たち 無事に逃げたかな？
Do you think the others got away?
Yeah, I think so.
うん… たぶんね
よかった…
Thank the Heavens.
Yeah.
１人じゃなくて よかった
I’m glad I’m not alone.
Happy that I’m in the same mess as you, huh?
せめて 俺を道連れにできたから
気が晴れた？
I think this would’ve been too much to bear alone.
１人だったら 本当に
絶対 耐えられなかったと思う
I wouldn’t have made it this far without you.
きっと ここまでだって
来られなかった
俺も 同じだよ
Me neither.
Episode 06
Escape
こんな所で死にたくないな
I don’t want to die here.
ダメに決まってんだろ？
Of course not!
真言は
誰にも教えちゃいけないんだ
We’re not supposed to tell anybody our mantras!
Come on, we’re friends!
いいじゃん 友達でしょ？
絶対 秘密にするからさ
I won’t tell anyone else.
ダメだって
No.
Aren’t you curious?
どんなのか気にならない？
自分のと どう違うのか とか
Don’t you want to know how it’s different from your own?
だったら 早季のを 言ってみろよ
Then you tell me yours.
Okay.
分かった
じゃあ こういうのは どう？
Then how about this?
お互いに真言を紙に書いて
１ ２の３で見せ合いっこするの
We write down our mantras on pieces of paper and show them to each other on the count of three.
う～ん… やっぱ ダメだ
Nah, I’d rather not.
Come on! We don’t have to show it long enough for the other person to remember it.
だから～ 別に覚えられるほど
ちゃんと見せなくていいんだって
Just flash it for a split second.
本当に ほんの 一瞬だけ
見せ合うの
そんなの 意味ねえだろ
Where’s the point in that?
It’ll be enough. We’ll get a sense of the length and feel.
それでいいのよ
どれぐらいの長さか とか
だいたいの感じが
つかめるでしょ？
じゃあ いい？ １ ２の３
Ready? One, two, three!
見えた？
Could you read it?
Not at all.
全然
でも 何となく長さは分かった
But I know how long it is.
そんなに長くなかったね
It’s really not that long.
ああ 早季のも そうだったな
Yeah. Neither is yours.
でも １文字くらい見えた？
Could you read any of it?
全然 だって 覚の字って
ちゃんと見ても 読めないもん
Nope.
Your handwriting is impossible to read even when I get a good look.
Shut up.
うるせ
Satoru…
覚… 覚？
Satoru?
Everyone… they’re…
朝比奈 覚
Asahina Satoru. Asahina Satoru.
朝比奈 覚 お前は規則を破って
来てはならないところに来た
You have violated the rules and
gone where you were not supposed to.
Furthermore, you have allowed your mind to be poisoned by a demon.
しかも 禁を犯して
悪魔の言葉に耳を傾けた
だが 問題は その先にある
The real problem, however, weighs far heavier.
You have violated the tenth precept of the Platinum Code,
the very basis of the Code of Ethics: The Four Tenets Against Evil.
お前たちは倫理規定の
さらに根底にある白金法
その第十条 悪謗四宝戒に背いた
悪魔の声に従い
仏の教えに異を唱えたのだ
You have listened to the demon and
turned against the Buddhist teachings.
よって 私は お前の呪力を
ただちに凍結せねばならない
Therefore, I am left with no choice but to seal your Cantus immediately.
炎を見なさい
Look at the flames.
お前の呪力は あの人形の中に
封印した 人形が見えるか？
Your Cantus is sealed inside this emblem.
Can you see the emblem?
はあ… はい
Yes.
今から 人形を火の中に くべる
一切を焼施すべし
I will now cast the emblem into the fire.
May your worldly desires be burned away.
The ash returns to the vast and wild earth.
すべての煩悩を焼尽せしめ
灰は無辺の荒土に還るべし
Look! The emblem has burned away!
見よ 人形は燃え尽きた
お前の呪力は ここに凍結された！
Your Cantus has been sealed here!
Cast away your worldly desires.
煩悩を捨てよ
解脱のためには すべてを
You must cast all of them into the
purging flames to reach enlightenment.
いったん 清浄な炎の中で
焼き尽くさなければならない
Asahina Satoru.
朝比奈 覚
お前は深く神仏に帰依し
You have shown great devotion and abandoned your Cantus.
自ら呪力を放てきした
されば
ここに 再度 正しき真言を授け
Now I shall teach you a pure mantra, summon a
new spirit and bestow Cantus upon you once more.
精霊を召喚し 呪力を返還する！
覚！
Satoru!
Satoru, you’re doing this, right?
覚 これ 覚がやってるのね？
I know it!
分かってる？ 呪力が戻ったのよ！
Your Cantus is back!
うん… そう みたいだ
Yeah, looks like it.
Quick! Blow a hole into the ceiling!
早く 天井に風穴を開けて！
邪魔な土を
どこかにやっちゃって！
Blast those rocks sky high!
分かった
Okay.
Wait! The poisonous gas might be covering the ground outside!
あ 待って 外には有毒ガスが
充満してるかも
Don’t worry.
大丈夫 全部 吹っ飛ばす
I’ll blow it all away.
やった！
You did it!
Yeah.
Wait!
待って！ 私が先に見てくる
I’ll go ahead and look around.
Don’t!
ダメだよ 土蜘蛛が
弓で狙っているかもしれないし
The Feral Spiders might be outside with their bows.
だから 私が先に行くのよ
That’s why I’m going first.
Well?
どう？
近くには 何もいない
There’s no one around.
I bet they’re somewhere in the area.
ヤツら 絶対 どっかにいるはずだ
There’s no way that little gust killed them all.
さっきの風ぐらいで
全滅するわけがない
あっ ねえ あそこ見て
何か 動いた
Look! There!
Something moved!
あっ… ごめん 錯覚だったのかな
Sorry. Maybe I was just imagining things.
If someone wanted to spread
poisonous gas, they’d do it from there.
この地形で毒ガスをまくなら
あそこが 一番いいはずだ
やっぱり！
I knew it!
Then let’s escape the other way!
じゃあ あっちへ逃げなきゃ！
あっ…
Don’t be stupid.
何 言ってんだよ？
逃げたりしたら
Running away will only make them pursue us.
ヤツらは 絶対 追いかけてくる
後ろから攻撃されたら
どうするんだ？
Do you want to be attacked from behind?
こっちから攻撃をかける
We have to take the fight to them.
ヤツらを全滅させない限り
安全とは言えない
We’re not safe until they’re all dead.
That’s crazy! I can’t help you in combat!
そんな 無理よ！
だって 戦えるのは覚だけなのに
坊さんが やられたのを
見ただろう？
You saw what happened to the monk!
Cantus isn’t suited for defense.
呪力は守りには向かない
We must use it offensively to survive.
攻撃に使ってこそ 生きるんだ
But you can run if you’re scared.
だけど 早季は恐いんなら
逃げても かまわないぜ
戦うのは 俺１人でいいから
I can do this alone.
はあ… そんなこと言われて
Do you expect me to just accept that and run now?
｢はい そうですか｣と
逃げるわけには いかないでしょ
We’re probably in range of their bows now.
もう 弓矢の射程に
入ってるだろうな
どうするの？
What now?
Let’s fire some bullets.
弾だ
飛べ！
Fly!
グア～！
Morons.
バカめ
グオオ～！
I’d love to make a blade storm like the monk…
本当は カマイタチを
作りたいんだけどな
しかたがない
Too bad I can’t.
Satoru…
覚？
行け
Go.
グオ～！ オオ…
フン 怖がってやんの
Look at how scared they are.
Let’s make this more interesting.
でも このままじゃ
少し芸がねえな…
よし 燃えろ！
Burn!
グオ～！
グア～！ ガガ…
グオ～！ グア…
Let’s go.
行くぞ
Okay.
あれ
Look!
毒ガスを作る機械じゃない？
Aren’t those the machines used
to make the poisonous gas?
Yeah.
ちょっと遊んでやろうか
Let’s have some fun here.
I see.
なるほど 力ずくでやるより
恐怖で あおった方が効果あんな
Fear is more effective against them than brute force.
どうして？
もう 追って来ないんじゃない？
Why? They won’t chase us anymore.
早く逃げようよ！
Let’s run away now!
No.
だめだ カヌーまで まだ遠い
It’s a long walk to our canoes.
土蜘蛛を全滅させるまで
安心できないよ
We’re not safe until all the Feral Spiders are dead.
But—
でも…
大丈夫だ
Trust me.
呪力が戻りゃ 怖い物は ない
Nothing to be afraid of now that my Cantus is back.
覚… どうしちゃったの…？
Satoru, what’s gotten into you?
You’re like a different person.
いつもの覚じゃないみたい
そうかな
Really?
だって 覚は…
You never used to…
だいたい土蜘蛛の竜穴が
どこにあるか 分かってるの？
Do you even know where the
Feral Spiders’ nest is to begin with?
場所も分かんないのに
やみくもに攻めるのは無理よ
You don’t even know where it is.
You can’t just launch an attack blindly.
神様！
Gods.
I am afraid that crossing this clearing is extremely dangerous.
この草原を まっすぐ突っ切るのは
きわめて危険と思われます
You would be completely visible from the other side,
向こうの森から丸見えですし
どこかに土蜘蛛の射手が
潜んでいる可能性もございます
and there is every possibility that
Feral Spider archers are hiding somewhere.
But their colony is over there in the woods, right?
でも 土蜘蛛コロニーは
あの森の中にあるんだろ？
こっから攻撃したって
相手が見えないんじゃ
I could attack from here,
but I’d be shooting blind and they’d just get away.
みすみす
取り逃がすだけじゃないか？
こんな草原くらい
簡単に焼き払ってやるのに
I could just set the clearing on fire, too…
おっしゃるとおりでございます
ですが たとえ１匹であっても
It is just as you say.
However, imagine if even a single surviving Feral Spider were to hide in the soil.
土蜘蛛が生き残り
土中に潜んでいた場合
I am afraid it would attempt to target you with poison arrows.
畏れ多くも 神様を
毒矢で狙ってくるやもしれません
土蜘蛛が使うのは
異国のカエルから取った
They use an extremely deadly poison
taken from frogs foreign to these lands.
命を奪う猛毒です
斥候が安全な
う回路を見つけておりますので
Our scouts have discovered a way to circle around them.
If you would please be so kind as to follow us…
どうか そちらを
お通りいただけますよう
お願い申し上げます
女王は無事なの？
はい
Is your queen all right?
Yes.
幸い 我々親衛隊が 安全な
場所へお運びいたしましたので
Luckily we, her elite guard, carried her to safety.
そう よかった
That’s good to hear.
Regrettably, all other members of the Robber Fly colony have fallen victim to the poisonous gas.
残念ながら 他の
塩谷虻コロニー構成員は
毒ガスで全滅しましたが
えっ…！
神様 どうか
あのような卑劣な戦法をとる
I beg you, gods, to teach the wicked Feral Spiders a lesson for using such cowardly means!
憎き土蜘蛛たちに 目に物を
言わせてやってくださいませ
I will.
分かってる
Will we really be safe on this path?
この道は 本当に安全なの？
ご心配には及びません
You need not worry.
先程 斥候を放ちましたが
敵兵の姿はありませんでした
We dispatched scouts in this direction earlier, and there were no signs of enemy movement.
ヤツらは毒ガスで 我々を
しとめたと思い込んでますから
They believe we have all been slain by the gas,
直後に本陣が急襲を受けるとは
想像もしていないはずです
so they will not be expecting an attack on their main base.
そう…
I see.
でも ちょっと待って
Hang on!
これで気が済んだ？
うん
Happy now?
Yeah.
本当に こんなんで大丈夫かよ？
Are you sure this will do the trick?
何もしないよりは 良いでしょ？
It’s better than doing nothing.
Why would we need a stand-in?
影武者なんて大げさだな
何？
神様 お隠れください！
What’s going on?
Gods, please hide yourselves!
The stand-in has been killed!
影がやられました！
神様 伏せてください
Take cover, gods!
どこ？
木の上です！
Where are they?
Atop the trees!
毒矢です！ 気をつけて！
Those are poison arrows! Be careful!
Protect Satoru!
覚を守って！
覚！ あの木よ 揺らしてみて！
Satoru! Shake that tree!
これ いったい何なの？
What is this?
Don’t be so surprised.
今さら 驚くなよ
昨日の晩 見た時だって
Remember last night?
Their troops had all sorts of monsters.
コイツらの軍隊は
化け物行列だったじゃないか
でも… じゃあ アイツらって
どんな形にでもなれるの？
But then…
Are you saying they can take all sorts of forms?
Why?
どうして？
それは まだわかんない
I don’t know.
まあ 仮説ならあるけど
I have a theory, though.
We should be careful.
気をつけた方がいいな
There’s no telling what form they’ll take to ambush us.
どんな擬態をして
待ち伏せているか分かんねえし
Then let’s turn back! It’s too dangerous here!
だったら 引き返そうよ！
やっぱ危険すぎるよ！
It’s too late to turn back now.
ここまで来たら 後戻りはできない
逃げればヤツらは 必ず追ってくる
They’ll give chase if we run.
Wait!
待って
ここ 何だかすごく嫌な感じがする
I’m getting a really bad feeling about this.
ワナがあるってこと？
Do you think it’s a trap?
わかんないけど…
I’m not sure…
大丈夫だ 行こう
Don’t worry. Let’s go.
…でも
But…
いくら何でも 哺乳類が
そんなに長く潜ってらんないよ
There’s no way mammals could stay underwater for so long.
Damn it! Those bastards!
畜生 ふざけやがって！
いいさ そのまま隠れてろ…
すっかり ゆで上がるまで
All right. Just stay hidden.
I’ll turn you into a stew.
Satoru…
覚…
覚 後ろにいる… 砂の下
Satoru, behind us.
Underground…
どこ？
１つは真後ろ ６ｍ～７ｍ
Where?
One is right behind us, about six or seven meters.
その右に２体 左斜め後ろに１体
Two others to its right and one more to its left about a meter behind it.
ふ～っ カエルは捨て駒だったのか
So the frogs were just a distraction?
油断なんねえな
ヤツら だまし討ちが得意なんだ
We’ve gotta stay alert.
Ambushes are their strong suit.
You look a bit tired, Satoru.
覚 少し疲れたんじゃない？
Not at all! I can do this.
そんなことねえよ このぐらい…
I think you should rest a little…
でも 少し休んだ方が
いいと思うけど…
危ない！
Watch out!
だいじょうぶだ みんな動くな！
Don’t worry. Stay put.
More incoming!
また来るわ！
戻れ
Go back.
やっつけた？
わかんねえ
Did you get them?
I don’t know.
Satoru!
覚！
くそ…！
Damn it!
後ろに！
Let’s retreat!
どっかにいる！
Where the hell are they?
敵が どっかから見てるんだ
早季！ 探してくれ！
They must be watching us from somewhere!
Saki, find them for me!
Okay!
Where are they?
どこ？
They’ve stopped attacking.
攻撃が途切れてる
It probably takes them a while to get the rocks ready.
向こうも 岩を準備する時間が
かかってるのかもしれない
There!
あれだわ！
あそこから 位置を知らせてる！
There’s their lookout!
今のうちよ 移動しなきゃ
いったん下がる？
We should move while we can!
Should we fall back?
いや 前進だ
No, we advance.
Satoru… Wait!
覚… 待ってよ！
Gods! Gods!
神様 神様
ご無事で何よりでございました
I am delighted to see you are unharmed.
こうなればもう こちらのものです
Victory is within our reach now.
どうか邪悪な土蜘蛛どもに
正義の鉄ついを下されますよう
Please bring down the iron hammer of judgment on the wicked Feral Spiders!
調子のいいことばっかり
言わないでよ！
Don’t sweet-talk us!
You said this path would be safe!
あんたが こっちの道が
安全だって言ったのよ！
いったい どこが安全なの？
そこら中 伏兵だらけじゃない！
How is this safe?!
It’s been nothing but ambushes!
誠に申し訳ございません
I am terribly sorry.
事前に 斥候を放って
安全を確認したのですが
We sent scouts ahead to find a safe path,
and there were no attacks whatsoever.
そのときは まったく
何の攻撃も受けなかったのです
当たり前でしょ？
Of course not!
They weren’t trying to ambush your scouts! They were waiting for us!
アイツらは あんたの斥候じゃなく
あたしたちを
待ち伏せしてたんだから！
It’s okay. What matters is that we’ve made it this far.
もう いい
とにかく ここまで来たんだから
さっさと片をつけて 家に帰るぞ
Let’s finish this and go home.
でも この先は通れないわ
But we can’t go this way.
We don’t know where the rocks are coming from.
どこから岩が飛んで来るか
分からないし
引き返すべきよ
We should turn back!
We can’t do that.
それはだめだ
もう 戦端は開かれてる
We’re already at war.
敵の真ん前で 回れ右するなんて
自殺行為だ
Running from the enemy is tantamount to suicide.
でも 竹林より先に出れば
岩が飛んでくるのよ？
But if we venture beyond that bamboo forest, the rocks will come flying.
So the forest is off limits, and
who knows what else awaits us?
だからといって
竹林の中を通ることもできないし
それこそ どんなワナがあるか
わからないでしょう？
We shall scout out the enemy.
私どもが 偵察に参ります
Once we know wherefrom they are targeting us with the rocks,
敵が 石を投てきしている場所を
見つけますので
あとは神様の お力で
一つずつ 潰していただければ…
you can purge them one by one with your powers.
簡単に言わないでよね！
You make it seem so simple!
Satoru’s tired!
覚は疲れてるんだから！
しまった… わたしが呪力を
使えないことがバレたかも…
Oh no!
They might realize that I can’t use my Cantus.
では
Excuse us.
シャワイ…
アワ…
On the other side of the bamboo forest,
there is a wide space unobstructed by trees.
竹林の向こうには
視界を遮るような木々もなく
かなり開けた場所になっています
敵の主力は
そこに散開している模様です
The enemy forces have congregated there.
But isn’t it to our advantage if they’re out in plain sight?
見通しが いいなら
こっちにも好都合じゃない
It is somewhat difficult to explain.
それが… 何と言っていいのか
どうか 直接ご覧になってください
Please be so kind as to look yourselves.
こんどこそ 竹林の中には
敵兵がいないことは
We have made sure that no enemy is hiding in the forest.
確認しておりますので
Whoa…
すごい…
何匹いるんだ…
How many of them are there?
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
It’s okay! Don’t worry!
大丈夫よ 安心して
絶対 家に帰れるから
We’ll make it home!
もしかすると 神様は もう
神様ではなくなったのですか？
Could it be that…
…you are no longer gods?
あなたの助けが必要なの
We need your help.
捕まった…
あそこに 奇狼丸がいる
They’ve got us.
That’s Kiroumaru.